auvik.com 2019-06-16

# Privacy Policy | Auvik Networks

Auvik Networks Inc. and its subsidiaries (“ **Auvik** ”, “ **Our** ”, “ **We** ” or “ **Us** ”) is committed to protecting the privacy and security of your Personal Information obtained by reason of your relationship with Auvik. This document is designed to explain the types of Personal Information we collect, how it is used, and the steps we take to ensure your Personal Information is handled appropriately.

This Privacy Policy applies to Personal Information collected by Auvik in connection with our operations and services, which includes Personal Information collected through our website, [auvik.com](https://www.auvik.com/), and its related subdomains and all other sites owned and operated by Auvik that redirect to auvik.com (the “Site”), as well as the services offered by Auvik (collectively, “ **Services** ” and each is a “ **Service** ”). This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and forms part of the terms of service for any applicable Service.

Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your Personal Information and how we will treat it. By using the Site, a Service, or otherwise providing us with your Personal Information, you acknowledge you have read and understood the practices described in this Privacy Policy, as they may be amended by us from time to time.

This Privacy Policy sets out:

  * What is Personal Information? 
    * Collection of your Personal Information
    * Information you provide
    * Information we collect from your use of the Site or a Service
    * Cookies and similar technologies
  * Why we use your Personal Information
    * Information you provide
    * Information we collect about you from your use of the Site or a Service
  * Our promotional updates and communications
  * Who your Personal Information is shared with
  * Where we store your Personal Information
  * Retention of your Personal Information
  * Third-party Links
  * How we safeguard your Personal Information
  * Your rights
  * Changes to this Privacy Policy
  * How to contact us

### What is Personal Information?

Personal information is any information that relates to an individual who can be identified directly or indirectly (including by referring to an identifier such as a name, an identification number or online identifier, or any other information about that person) and is recorded in any form.

_Collection of your Personal Information_

Auvik collects only the Personal Information required to market and provide products and services to you. The amount of Personal Information provided by you and collected by Auvik depends on the circumstances and the Personal Information we collect, including contact, demographic, or other types of information.

We collect and process the following types of information from you:

_Information you provide:_

We may occasionally request from you or you may otherwise voluntarily provide us with Personal Information. In particular when you:

  * Sign up for a Service, register for an event or webinar 
    * We collect information identifying your organization as our customer and your information as the contact at the customer, in particular your first name, last name, email address, telephone number and a password associated with your account.
  * Open an account with us, as a user of a Service 
    * as a user authorized to access a Service provided by us on behalf of your organization (and our customer) we will collect information to enable us to authenticate your access to the Service including your first name, last name, email, address and a password associated with your account.
  * Fill in online forms or communicate with us by phone, email, or otherwise in order to receive information, make a comment or inquiry, or to report and seek to resolve a problem.
  * Make a payment, for a paid service provided by us, our payment processing vendor Zuora, collects your credit card information and billing address. Please see ‘Who your Personal Information is shared with’ for more information on processing of Personal Information by our payment processing vendor.

_Information we collect from your use of the Site or a Service_

Whenever you interact with us through the Site or a Service we automatically collect the following information from you each time you visit our Site or use our Service:

  * Technical information 
    * **IP Information** – In general, we collect and use information and data regarding your access to and use of the Site and the Services. When you use a web browser to visit the Site or use the Services, we record the information that your browser automatically sends whenever visiting or using any of the Services, including your web request, the Internet Protocol (“IP”) address and browser configuration of your Device (as defined below), the date and time of your request, and the uniform resource locator of the referring and/or exiting websites. In this Privacy Policy, “Device” means a computer, mobile phone, handset, tablet, or other device enabled for internet access and/or communication.
    * **Information about your visit** – In particular, the Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through, and from our Site and Service (including date and time), content viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visit to certain Site pages or the duration of a signed-in session on a Service, content interaction information, (such as scrolling, clicks, or mouse-overs) on the Site or actions performed by a logged-in user of a Service and any contact details used to reach our customer sales or support team.
    * **Local Software** – Some features of the Services may enable or require that you install local software (e.g. Auvik collector). This software may collect data from your local environment in order to provide the Services that you have requested. Local collectors may also collect telemetry information that will be sent to Auvik for operating and improving the Services. For more information about collectors, please consult the relevant terms of service for such Services.
    * **Geographic Location data** – We collect information through the Site as to your country of location by reference to your IP in order to deliver content or services dependent on knowing where you are. This information is collected in combination with a cookie associated with your Device to enable us to recognize your browser or Device when you return to the Site.
    * **User hosted data** – In providing a Service we host or may have access to user data, in the context of providing customer support services to users about their network environment. Such data is processed only under instructions of the user who remains the data controller to the extent any personal data is processed.

_Cookies and similar technologies:_

Auvik uses cookies and other similar technologies such as pixel tags, web beacons device-IDs (together “cookies”) to collect and store certain information. Cookies are small data files that are saved to your Device when you visit the Site and use the Services. Auvik may use both “session” cookies and “persistent” cookies. A session cookie is only active while you are on the Site or Service and is deleted once you close your browser. Unlike a session cookie, a persistent cookie is not deleted when you close your browser and will persist on your Device for longer.

Auvik uses cookies to identify when you return to the Site, save login information (but never passwords) associated with authenticating access to a Service, track usage statistics, and store your preferences across the Site and the Service. By default, most browsers will automatically accept cookies, but by altering your browser’s settings, you can either disable cookies completely or be prompted prior to a cookie being loaded. Consult each individual browser’s “help” feature for more information.

We use cookies and similar technologies where they are necessary on the grounds of the performance of a contract with you where we are authenticating you as an authorized user of a Service provided by us on behalf of your organization as our customer or because using cookies is in our legitimate interests, (where we have considered that these are not overridden by your rights) in the case of cookies that are strictly necessary for the operation of our Site and Services and in other cases where you have consented to their use as described further below:

_Strictly necessary cookies:_ These are cookies that are required for the operation of our Site or our Services under our terms with you. They include the cookies that enable you to log-in to our Services or secure areas of our Site.

_Analytics:_ Portions of the Site and Services also use analytical tools (collectively, “ **Analytical Tools** ”) that are operated by us and third-party providers, such as Google Inc., which may use cookies, web beacons, scripts, and similar means for the purpose of collecting information and analyzing how you use the Site and our Services. Information collected using Analytical Tools will be transmitted and stored on servers located in the United States. The third-party providers of Analytical Tools may also transfer this information to other third parties (such as governmental authorities) where they are required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on their behalf. As some Analytical Tools rely on cookies to perform their functions, you can opt out of Google Analytics. [tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

_Google Display Advertising:_ The Site also uses Google Display Advertising. Google Display Advertising enables features in the Google Analytics service that are not available through the standard implementation. These additional features enable Retargeting with Google Analytics, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, Google Display Network Impression Reporting and the DoubleClick Campaign Manager integration.  
Implementing Retargeting with Google Analytics means that third-party vendors, including Google, may show our ads on websites across the internet. Auvik and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads to you when you are visiting other websites based on your past visits to our Site.

Implementing Google Display Network Impression Reporting and the DoubleClick Campaign Manager means that Auvik and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to report how our ad impressions, other uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to our Site.

The data we gather from Google’s Interest-based advertising or third-party audience data (such as age, gender, and interests) through Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting is used to better understand the demographic to which our services appeal so that we can display our ads to those who would benefit from our Services and not to those who would not benefit.

If you would like to opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads, you can do so by going to [www.google.com/settings/ads](http://www.google.com/settings/ads).

You can also learn more about turning off advertising cookies by visiting [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)

### Why we collect and use your Personal Information

Auvik identifies the purpose for which your Personal Information is collected and will be used or disclosed. If that purpose is not listed below, we will identify any additional purposes for which we will collect your Personal Information, before or at the time of collection, and we will obtain your consent to collect, use, or disclose your Personal Information for such additional purpose(s).  
We use information held about you in the following ways:

_Information you provide:_

We will use this information to:

  * Take steps in order to enter into any contract or carry out our obligations arising from any contract entered into between us including: 
    * Services requested by you and conducted on your behalf;
    * processing and keeping track of transactions and reporting back to you;
    * protecting against fraud or error;
    * administering and managing the Services and our business operations;
    * notifying you about changes to our Services
    * When you send email or other communications to us, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests, and improve the Services.
  * Provide you with information about our goods or services we feel may interest you if you have given your consent to receive marketing material from us at the point we collect your information where required by law or otherwise in our legitimate interests provided these interests do not override your right to object to such communications. See ‘Our promotional updates and communications‘
  * Ensure in our legitimate interests that: 
    * Content from our Site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your Device.
    * We provide you with the information and Services that you request from us.

_Information we collect about you from your use of the Site or a Service_

We use this information in our legitimate interests, where we have considered these are not overridden by your rights:

  * to personalize your experience with the Site, as well as evaluate statistics on Site activity;
  * to keep our Site and Services safe and secure;
  * to perform statistical analysis of your behavior and characteristics, in order to measure interest in and use of the various sections of the Site;
  * for measuring or understanding the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and to deliver relevant advertising to you on other websites;
  * for complying with legal and governmental requirements; and/or
  * to improve our Site and Services to ensure that content is presented and available in the most effective manner for you and your Device.

Otherwise, we will obtain your express consent (by verbal, written, or electronic agreement) to collect, use, or disclose your Personal Information.

### Our promotional updates and communications

Where permitted in our legitimate interest or with your prior consent where required by law, we will use your Personal Information collected in the context of our Site or in offering our Services for marketing analysis and to provide you with promotional update communications by email about our Services.

You can object to further marketing at any time by updating your communication preferences by clicking the “Manage Subscription” link at the end of all our marketing and promotional update communications to you, or by sending us an email to [unsubscribe@auvik.com](mailto:unsubscribe@auvik.com).

### Who your Personal Information is shared with

Except as set out in this Privacy Policy, Auvik does not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personal Information.

We may transfer your Personal Information to trusted third-party service providers who assist us in administering our Site and providing our Services in accordance with our instructions and as required by Law. Examples of where we may disclose Personal Information to such third-party service providers include data analysis, marketing assistance, and customer service support. These third-party service providers will have access to your Personal Information that is needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes. We may use service providers who process and store Personal Information in other countries. See ‘Where we store your personal information‘ below.

We may disclose your Personal Information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our policies, or protect our or others’ rights or property, or for safety.

Information, including Personal Information, which we collect about our customers, visitors to the Site, users and others, is considered to be a business asset. As a result, in the unlikely event that we go out of business, enter bankruptcy, or if we are acquired as a result of a transaction such as a merger, acquisition, or asset sale, your Personal Information may be disclosed or transferred to the third-party acquirer in connection with the transaction.  
If your Personal Information is shared with third parties, those third parties are trusted third parties and bound by appropriate agreements as required with Auvik to secure and protect the confidentiality of your Personal Information.

A full list of organisations with whom we share Personal Information can be found here.

### Where we store your Personal Information

The Personal Information that we collect from you may be transferred to and stored in different countries to those from which you access our Services.

Where you are accessing our Site or Services from within the European Economic Area (“EEA”) the Personal Information that we collect or process from you may be transferred to and stored at a destination outside the EEA that may not be subject to equivalent Data Protection Law. Where your Personal Information is transferred outside the EEA, we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your Personal Information is subject to appropriate safeguards, such as relying on a recognized legal adequacy mechanism that is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

We transfer your personal information:

  * In order to store it
  * In order to deliver Services to you under our contract with you. This includes order fulfillment and provision of support services.
  * Where we are legally required to do so
  * In order to facilitate the operation of our group of businesses, where it is in our legitimate interests and we have concluded that these are not overridden by your rights.

Details of our transfers of your Personal Information and the relevant safeguards are set out here.

### Retention of your Personal Information

Auvik retains your Personal Information only as long as it is required for our business relationship, our contractual obligations to you, as required by applicable laws, or to identify or resolve legal issues or claims. We may also retain aggregate information beyond this time for research purposes and to help us develop and improve our services. You cannot be identified from aggregate information retained or used for these purposes.

### Third-Party Links

Auvik may at times provide a link to a third-party website or service. This Privacy Policy only addresses the use and disclosure of information collected from the use of our Site and Services. Links to third-party websites or services are intended for convenience only. We make no representations or warranties about the privacy practices of any such third-party website or service. As third-party websites and services are wholly independent from Auvik, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of third parties or the content of linked third-party websites. Therefore, access to any third-party websites or services is entirely at your own risk and it is your responsibility to take all protective measures to guard against viruses or other destructive devices and programs. You should refer to the privacy policies of third parties if you have any questions.

### How we safeguard your Personal Information

Auvik uses reasonable security measures to safeguard your Personal Information, regardless of the format in which it is held, including, but not limited to: (i) physical security measures; (ii) electronic security measures for computerized personal information; (iii) organizational processes; and (iv) contractual obligations with third parties who need access to your Personal Information requiring them to protect and secure your Personal Information.

### Your rights

  * You have the right under certain circumstances: 
    * to be provided with a copy of your Personal Information held by us;
    * to request the rectification or erasure of your Personal Information held by us;
    * to request that we restrict the processing of your Personal Information (while we verify or investigate your concerns with this information, for example);
    * to object to the further processing of your Personal Information, including the right to object to marketing as mentioned in ‘Our promotional updates and communications‘ section;
    * to request that your provided Personal Information be moved to a third party.
  * Your right to withdraw consent:

Where the processing of your Personal Information by us is based on consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent without detriment at any time by contacting us. You can also change your marketing preferences at any time as described in ‘Our promotional updates and communications‘ section.

You can also exercise the rights listed above at any time by contacting the Data Protection Officer at [privacy@auvik.com](mailto:privacy@auvik.com).

If your request or concern is not satisfactorily resolved by us, you may approach your local data protection authority. See <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/dataprotection/bodies/authorities/index_en.html>. The [Information Commissioner](http://www.ico.org.uk/) is the supervisory authority in the UK.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Auvik reserves the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy. As such, we encourage you to review this Privacy Policy regularly to stay up to date on our policies. In such a case, we will update the effective date of the updated policy and in relation to substantive changes may notify you by email. You may find the current effective date at the end of this Privacy Policy.

### How to contact us

If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policy or privacy practices, you may contact Auvik directly.

If you are outside Europe you should contact:

> Auvik Networks Inc:  
>  451 Phillip Street, Suite 200  
>  Waterloo, ON N2L 3X2
> 
> Email: [privacy@auvik.com](mailto:privacy@auvik.com)

If you are in Europe you can contact:

> Auvik Networks:  
>  Building 5, Level 2  
>  Caldecotte Lake Business Park  
>  Caldecotte Lake Drive  
>  Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire  
>  MK7 8LF
> 
> Email: [privacy@auvik.com](mailto:privacy@auvik.com)

* * *

_This version of this Privacy Policy is effective as of May 2019_

Hi! Looks like you have JavaScript disabled. Please turn it on so you can see and interact with everything on our site.
